<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pietro F. Maggi</title>
    <link>http://pietromaggi.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pietro F. Maggi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2013-2017 Pietro F. Maggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 21:30:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://pietromaggi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Here be Dragons - The Enterprise Mobile Security Journey</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2018/04/14/here-be-dragons---the-enterprise-mobile-security-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 21:30:48 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2018/04/14/here-be-dragons---the-enterprise-mobile-security-journey/</guid>
      <description>Note:
This blog started out as a series of notes for a talk I&#39;ve presented in April 2018 at a couple of events (Droidcon Dubai and Droidcon Turin) with my Zebra Technologies hat. Feel free to provide comments and feedback.  Looking at what is trendy at technology conferences, you can find a lot of talks about JavaScript frameworks or [functional|concatenative|multi-paradigm] programming languages, so when I started to work on my new talk I felt that I had to explain the title a little bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Browser - Modernizing web applications</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2018/03/21/enterprise-browser---modernizing-web-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 21:30:48 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2018/03/21/enterprise-browser---modernizing-web-applications/</guid>
      <description>Note: This blog describe the contente presented during Zebra Technologies&amp;rsquo; DEVTALK recorded March 21st 2018 about Enterprise Browser. You can find a recording of the presentation on Zebra&amp;rsquo;s Developer Portal.
Modernize Web Application  Enterprise Browser is not just a browser, it&amp;rsquo;s a business enabler that Symbol, Motorola, Motorola Solutions and now Zebra has developed over the last 15 years.
 
I know that fancy tag line remembers those cats&amp;rsquo; posters: but it&amp;rsquo;s true!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking Appointments</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 21:53:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/speaking/</guid>
      <description>ARCHIVE AND TALK LINKS  20-Apr-18 - Droidcon Turin - Here be Dragons - The Enterprise Mobile Security Journey.  13-Apr-18 - Droidcon Dubai - Here be Dragons - The Enterprise Mobile Security Journey. 04-Sep-17 - Droidcon Berlin- Android Security, an Enterprise Perspective.  14-16 June - Zebra&amp;rsquo;s AppForum EMEA in Prague  With Darryn Campbell: What&amp;rsquo;s The Difference in Android L,M,N,and O Migrating from Win Mobile to Android Create Scanning Applications Across Multiple Android Devices  07-Apr-17 - droidcon Turin 2017 - Android Security, an Enterprise perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Auto testing</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2017/10/31/android-auto-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2017/10/31/android-auto-testing/</guid>
      <description>Android Auto? Why? This summer I bought a new car and it came with a nice 8&amp;rdquo; touch panel that supports Android Auto and Apple Car.
It even came with seven seats and a nice engine, and that was way more important than having an additional screen&amp;hellip; but, it&amp;rsquo;s there, and I started to make good use of it.
Playing with Android Auto is a bit of a hit and miss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips on how to demo Android devices</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2017/10/13/tips-on-how-to-demo-android-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 17:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2017/10/13/tips-on-how-to-demo-android-devices/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever presented a new Android device to a tech crowd trying to explain some feature?
it happens to me quite a lot and over time I built my little bag of tricks on how to do it.
1. Use Vysor to show my device on the screen Vysor is my go-to solution for showing my device screen on the PC during demo. The only requirement in this case is to have adb enabled on your device and having a working adb on your PC/mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>droidcon Berlin 2017 Day 0 - the best Android community event!</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2017/09/10/droidcon-berlin-2017-day-0---the-best-android-community-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2017/09/10/droidcon-berlin-2017-day-0---the-best-android-community-event/</guid>
      <description>Another year, another droidcon Berlin.
This year I decided to took some detailed notes. This is the report for the first day, Sunday September 3rd, I&amp;rsquo;ll add a couple of other posts for the main conference days.
Day 0 - Sunday September 3rd The event this year started on Sunday September 3rd with a barcamp, and a panel on data persistency.
Being there for setting up the booth in the morning I pitched a talk about &amp;laquo;Barcode Scanning on Android&amp;raquo; in Android and got accepted straight away&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s incredible the interest in this technology that was invented the same year I was born, 1970&amp;hellip; is this a coincidence?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Android `sdk.dir` property to locate EMDK&#39;s jar Library.</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2017/08/08/using-android-sdk.dir-property-to-locate-emdks-jar-library./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 17:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2017/08/08/using-android-sdk.dir-property-to-locate-emdks-jar-library./</guid>
      <description>Note this post has been published on Zebra developer portal, if you&amp;rsquo;ve any comment, probably best to post them over there.
Working in Android Studio you can notice that every project contains a local.properties file with at least a couple of properties containing the path for Android SDK and Android NDK.
Android Studio populates this information when it creates the project based on the ANDROID_HOME environment variable. If this variable is not present in your system Android Studio will find the correct path in other ways, but having ANDROID_HOME setup correctly is a really good idea, see the note at the end of this short post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toggling MC18 Navigation (and Status) Bar visible state</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/10/30/toggling-mc18-navigation-and-status-bar-visible-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/10/30/toggling-mc18-navigation-and-status-bar-visible-state/</guid>
      <description>MC18 is the only Zebra Android mobile computer (at least till now) that uses a Navigation bar instead of phisycal buttons for the back and home. This is the first device where it makes sense to use Android immersive mode!
The problem with the standard immersive mode is that swiping from the bottom or the top of the screen re-enable both Navigation and Status bar. It&amp;rsquo;s not really intended to be a kiosk mode&amp;hellip; is just to have a full screen capability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Browser and DataWedge on Android - friends at the end</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/10/29/enterprise-browser-and-datawedge-on-android---friends-at-the-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/10/29/enterprise-browser-and-datawedge-on-android---friends-at-the-end/</guid>
      <description>During Enterprise Browser hands-on lab, I got some enquiry about using other MobilityDNA utilities together with EB; in particular how to integrate SwipeAssist and Simulscan. These utilities can be integrated, with some heavy lifting, and accepting some constraints.
Some background The current scanner framework implementation on our Android devices make available a single scanner object that provides full Scanner control. As always &amp;hellip;&amp;laquo;with great power comes great responsibility&amp;raquo;: an application using the scanner object from the Barcode API, is required to release it when it&amp;rsquo;s going in the background (usually you do this handling in the onPause() callback in your native application).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling Home Button on Zebra Android devices</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/08/01/disabling-home-button-on-zebra-android-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/08/01/disabling-home-button-on-zebra-android-devices/</guid>
      <description>Intro I presented in the past a method to disable the Home Button on Zebra&amp;rsquo;s MC40 Android device, using a custom intent1. After having published it, I got some enquiries, about having the same behaviour on other Zebra&amp;rsquo;s devices. Well, it turns out that there&amp;rsquo;s now a &amp;laquo;standard&amp;raquo; way to do this in Zebra&amp;rsquo;s Mx extension using the UI Manager profile. This post is going to show how to implement a simple application that can disable the Home Button on all Zebra&amp;rsquo;s devices that have Mx v4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Display AutoRotation from StageNow</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/06/07/managing-display-autorotation-from-stagenow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/06/07/managing-display-autorotation-from-stagenow/</guid>
      <description>Another busy day with enquiry about our devices/tools.
The funny thing is that, most of the time, answer to a question with another one is actually a good strategy :-)
This one cames from my colleague Raymond:
 Can we launch an adb commands from Stagenow?
 The quick answer is no, the right answer is: what are you trying to achieve?
 I need a way to disable the Disaply AutoRotate setting, something that is possible to do using an adb shell command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling MC40 Home Button with a custom intent</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/18/disabling-mc40-home-button-with-a-custom-intent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/18/disabling-mc40-home-button-with-a-custom-intent/</guid>
      <description>Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve published another post that explain how to disable the Home Button on all the Zebra&amp;rsquo;s Android devices that are supported by Mx v4.3+.
Intro Zebra Technologies&amp;rsquo; devices are purpose built to be single use devices. Having an OS like Android nowadays provides a lot of flexibility&amp;hellip; sometimes a bit too much.
With this idea in mind, the Android version used on these devices sometimes provide some nice surprise, like an Intent to disable the omnipresent Android&amp;rsquo;s Home button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secondary External Storage in Android KitKat - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/14/secondary-external-storage-in-android-kitkat---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 23:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/14/secondary-external-storage-in-android-kitkat---part-1/</guid>
      <description>First technical post for 2016. Finally!
To kick-start 2016 I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen a topic that is more and more relevant in our market: The changes introduced by Google in Android v4.4 KitKat, regarding the secondary storage (the SDCard).
I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about this in my AppForum 2015 talk last October in London1, but I want to add some extra info and rationales here.
A bit of background Android&amp;rsquo;s purpose is to establish an open platform for developers to build innovative apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 20:50:38 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Pietro F. Maggi, I&amp;rsquo;m a Father an Husband and occasionally I find the time to write some code.
I really believe that the best way to learn how something works is to take it apart (I know, I can&amp;rsquo;t really blame my kids when they do the same).
I&amp;rsquo;ve more than fifteen years designing and developing software solutions with a deep mobile experience. I frequently speak at conferences and Zebra Technologies events to present DevTools for Enterprise mobility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/09/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 20:50:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/09/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Time for revamping a bit this blog.
From a technical point of view, I struggled with octopress v2.x to keep this blog aligned across the multiple machine I use in my work/life. Octopress v3 is supposed to solve most of the issue that plagued me over these years but, I wanted to test something a bit different.
New year new static blog generator. Given that I want to spend some time evaluating Go I decided to give Hugo a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Zebra&#39;s EMDK project using SDK Platform 23</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2015/11/25/building-zebras-emdk-project-using-sdk-platform-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 09:54:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2015/11/25/building-zebras-emdk-project-using-sdk-platform-23/</guid>
      <description>Note: EMDK 4.0 is now documenting this method to add com.symbol.emdk.jar as a dependency There&amp;rsquo;s a recurring question coming to me and to Launchpad&amp;rsquo;s forums lately:
How can I compile my Android app, using Zebra&amp;rsquo;s EMDK, if I need the latest support library?
Some background With the Android tools moving super-fast (Android studio v1.0 launched at the beginning of 2015, the latest stable release is v1.4.1, we already have v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slide Decks</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/decks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 19:31:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/decks/</guid>
      <description>Android Wireless DeepDive Exploring how to build a RhoMobile native extension for an Android undocumented feature.
Mobile Barcode Scanning API Status An analysis of barcode scanning API status on mobile devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Back Button and Enterprise Browser</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2015/09/25/android-back-button-and-enterprise-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 11:33:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2015/09/25/android-back-button-and-enterprise-browser/</guid>
      <description>Edit Enteprise Browser v1.3 introduced a change that requires to enable FunctionKeysCapturable to be able to use the KeyCapture API.
To do this you need to update your Config.xml with:
&amp;lt;FunctionKeysCapturable value=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;  Enterprise Browser Enterprise Browser is Zebra Technologies&amp;rsquo; Industrial Browser built for our Rugged Devices, we support most of our Windows Mobile/Windows CE devices and Android devices.
This product is usually used with existing web application that cannot be updated/modified moving from one device to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the SDCard Path on Android devices</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/10/19/finding-the-sdcard-path-on-android-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 20:55:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/10/19/finding-the-sdcard-path-on-android-devices/</guid>
      <description>With Motorola Solutions we&amp;rsquo;re busy finishing the first round of Android Developer&amp;rsquo;s Kitchens around Europe. Just in time to prepare for the Enterprise App Forum in Brussels!.
The nice things of these events is the interaction with our partners and theirs real live problem!
Last week I got an interesting question regarding our TC55:
How can I programmatically get the path for the SDCard on the TC55?
That&amp;rsquo;s a good question; usually you don&amp;rsquo;t want to insert in your code the dependency to an hard coded path!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting device info from MSI Android devices</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/09/02/getting-device-info-from-msi-android-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 11:56:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/09/02/getting-device-info-from-msi-android-devices/</guid>
      <description>The good old ways! On Symbol/MSI Windows Mobile devices, we where providing some APIs in the EMDK to get additional information. Looking into the Resource Coordinator is possible to find APIs like:
 RCM_GetESN() - retrieves the device electronic serial number RCM_GetUniqueUnitId() - retrieves the unique unit identification number RCM_GetVersion() - retrieves version information etc&amp;hellip;  &amp;hellip;and we don&amp;rsquo;t have anything like this in the Android EMDK. WHY?
Simply because the functionality is already included in the standard Android SDK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhodes 5.0.2 and Visual Studio 2008 Localized edition</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/08/22/rhodes-5.0.2-and-visual-studio-2008-localized-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 13:01:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/08/22/rhodes-5.0.2-and-visual-studio-2008-localized-edition/</guid>
      <description>Oh the joy of a new RhoMobile version!
Creating new virtual machines and finally deciding that is time to leave the old trusty Windows XP and jump on the new Windows 7 with 63+1 bits. Oh man! what a pleasant use of time :-)
On top of this I wanted to spin the setup a bit and decided to use a localized version of Visual Studio 2008&amp;hellip; what can go wrong with it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring RhoMobile Suite v5.0 on a clean OS X Mavericks machine</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/08/11/configuring-rhomobile-suite-v5.0-on-a-clean-os-x-mavericks-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 09:57:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/08/11/configuring-rhomobile-suite-v5.0-on-a-clean-os-x-mavericks-machine/</guid>
      <description>RhoMobile Suite v5.0 The new main release of Rhodes, RhoElements and RhoConnect had just been released a couple of weeks ago during OSCON. It&amp;rsquo;s now time to install it and start building some mobile apps!
In this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to help you installing RMSv5.0 on a new OS X Mavericks machine and install everything that is needed to build iOS and Android applications, the only pre-requisite is to have a valid OS X Mavericks license installed on a Mac or inside a virtual machine&amp;hellip; on a Mac :-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little command line tricks</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/10/little-command-line-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 19:37:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/10/little-command-line-tricks/</guid>
      <description>This is a different blog, more a remainder for me than anything else. Hope that someone else can find these useful&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;re for me!
Recover a failed download with curl: curl -C - -o partially_downloaded_file &#39;www.example.com/path/to/the/file&#39;  Burn a playable DVD from a VIDEO_TS folder After searching the forums and trying various things, I still couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a quick, reliable, free method of burning a VIDEO_TS folder to a pure UDF DVD, so that it would play in regular DVD players, as well trigger DVD Player to start up automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving into Android source code</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/02/diving-into-android-source-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 14:34:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/02/diving-into-android-source-code/</guid>
      <description>Why dive into Android code? When you&amp;rsquo;ve to write applications for Android, you&amp;rsquo;re targeting a giant moving API surface, sometimes you can be surprised of some different behavior in different Android versions or with an API call that is not well documented, so having the option to delve into Android Source Code is a great opportunity.
A lot of things can be written on how to do this, there&amp;rsquo;s some documentation available on AOSP website, however I think that the best starting point is a video tutorial by NewCircle&amp;rsquo;s Instructor Dave Smith on this very topic:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 New Year resolutions</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/01/2014-new-year-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 17:41:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/01/2014-new-year-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>Blog a bit more That&amp;rsquo;s been one of my goal for a long time, and something that I always suggest to people to increase their &amp;laquo;Luck Surface Area&amp;raquo;.
In my case I can add an additional goal: keep track of what I do, tricks that I find and document procedure, fixes and workarounds. That&amp;rsquo;s always a bit of a pain point for me: I manage to do something and then in six months (or six hours) I forgot how I&amp;rsquo;ve done it and I need to start from scratch&amp;hellip; Never More</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 in numbers</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/31/2013-in-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 20:52:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/31/2013-in-numbers/</guid>
      <description>What an interesting year! This is the first year that I joined a regional team and this involved a lot of travel (12900 flight hours) across all EMEA. Has been a blast meeting a lot of end-users, partners and colleagues.
I&amp;rsquo;ve started doing my &amp;laquo;RhoMobile Developer Roadshow&amp;raquo;, usually a one man show with up to three events a week for a total of 22 cities, from Lisbon to Dubai, and from Capetown to Helsinki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhodes tips &amp; tricks</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/30/rhodes-tips--tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 13:56:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/30/rhodes-tips--tricks/</guid>
      <description>How to rebuild the rhodes gem git clone https://github.com/rhomobile/rhodes.git cd rhodes git checkout 3-5-stable  make and commit changes if needed, then:
rm -rf * git reset --hard git pull  Otherwise directly
rake gem  Copy files where you need it (on a different machine) gem install -l rhodes-3.5.1.13.2 (version given as an example)
Rhodes Database encryption Rhodes uses SQLite as database engine on all the supported platforms and, to provide encryption support we use different solutions depending by the target platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Version Manager (aka RVM) the Swiss army knife of Ruby versions</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/29/ruby-version-manager-aka-rvm-the-swiss-army-knife-of-ruby-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 17:24:54 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/29/ruby-version-manager-aka-rvm-the-swiss-army-knife-of-ruby-versions/</guid>
      <description>How many versions of Ruby do you need on your machine? Even if OS X 10.9 Mavericks came with Ruby v2.0.0-p195, the previous OS X versions where released with Ruby v1.8.7. On top of this, most of the work I do with Rhodes is still based on Ruby v1.9.3. And Ruby v2.1.0 has just been released! with some nice changes. Particularly interesting in Ruby v2.1 is the new Garbage Collector</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I like to talk about open source projects</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/28/why-i-like-to-talk-about-open-source-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 21:33:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/28/why-i-like-to-talk-about-open-source-projects/</guid>
      <description>Since I joined the RhoMobile group of Motorola Solutions as EIA pre-sale Technical Architect, I started to get disparate question regarding features of the Suite.
Something on the line:
 How is possible to launch an external application from a Rhodes one? I tried different APIs and nothing seems to work&amp;hellip; Looking on the support matrix of the APIs for different OSes, it seems that X is supported on platform Y but I&amp;rsquo;m not able to make it working&amp;hellip;  Usually I try to figure out the answer for these question by myself, it&amp;rsquo;s always useful getting a better understanding of the tool I usually talk about (and it&amp;rsquo;s probably the part of my job that I like the most: finding solutions to problems).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/license/</guid>
      <description>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/privacy_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/privacy_policy/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Privacy matters but it can be confusing. This page explains our approach to privacy on all our websites and how it affects you.
Short version We collect anonymous statistics about your visit, like which of our pages you viewed. Some 3rd parties like Facebook and Twitter may know you visited this website, if you use their services. We can’t control them but we don’t believe this knowledge poses any threat to you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>