<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Enterprise Browser on Pietro F. Maggi</title>
    <link>http://pietromaggi.com/tags/enterprise-browser/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Enterprise Browser on Pietro F. Maggi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2013-2018 Pietro F. Maggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 18:00:48 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://pietromaggi.com/tags/enterprise-browser/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Browser - Using the Android Headset as a Barcode Trigger</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2018/07/12/enterprise-browser---using-the-android-headset-as-a-barcode-trigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 18:00:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2018/07/12/enterprise-browser---using-the-android-headset-as-a-barcode-trigger/</guid>
      <description>What if&amp;hellip;
you want to use a Zebra&amp;rsquo;s Android device mounted on an arm-mount and you want to control the barcode scanner with a wired button?
WT6000 is the obvious answer!
But if your customer has already chosen the TC51 for other activities, we can help them using the headset connector.
The Android headset connectors Before Apple decided that we don&amp;rsquo;t need anymore the 3.5mm headset connector on our phones, people started to look into it as a standard input interface for all the devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Browser and DataWedge on Android - friends at the end</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/10/29/enterprise-browser-and-datawedge-on-android---friends-at-the-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/10/29/enterprise-browser-and-datawedge-on-android---friends-at-the-end/</guid>
      <description>During Enterprise Browser hands-on lab, I got some enquiry about using other MobilityDNA utilities together with EB; in particular how to integrate SwipeAssist and Simulscan. These utilities can be integrated, with some heavy lifting, and accepting some constraints.
Some background The current scanner framework implementation on our Android devices make available a single scanner object that provides full Scanner control. As always &amp;hellip;&amp;laquo;with great power comes great responsibility&amp;raquo;: an application using the scanner object from the Barcode API, is required to release it when it&amp;rsquo;s going in the background (usually you do this handling in the onPause() callback in your native application).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Back Button and Enterprise Browser</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2015/09/25/android-back-button-and-enterprise-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 11:33:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2015/09/25/android-back-button-and-enterprise-browser/</guid>
      <description>Edit Enteprise Browser v1.3 introduced a change that requires to enable FunctionKeysCapturable to be able to use the KeyCapture API.
To do this you need to update your Config.xml with:
&amp;lt;FunctionKeysCapturable value=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;  Enterprise Browser Enterprise Browser is Zebra Technologies&amp;rsquo; Industrial Browser built for our Rugged Devices, we support most of our Windows Mobile/Windows CE devices and Android devices.
This product is usually used with existing web application that cannot be updated/modified moving from one device to another.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>