<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sample on Pietro F. Maggi</title>
    <link>https://pietromaggi.com/tags/sample/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sample on Pietro F. Maggi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2013-2018 Pietro F. Maggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 17:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pietromaggi.com/tags/sample/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling Home Button on Zebra Android devices</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2016/08/01/disabling-home-button-on-zebra-android-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2016/08/01/disabling-home-button-on-zebra-android-devices/</guid>
      <description>Intro I presented in the past a method to disable the Home Button on Zebra&amp;rsquo;s MC40 Android device, using a custom intent1. After having published it, I got some enquiries, about having the same behaviour on other Zebra&amp;rsquo;s devices. Well, it turns out that there&amp;rsquo;s now a &amp;laquo;standard&amp;raquo; way to do this in Zebra&amp;rsquo;s Mx extension using the UI Manager profile. This post is going to show how to implement a simple application that can disable the Home Button on all Zebra&amp;rsquo;s devices that have Mx v4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling MC40 Home Button with a custom intent</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/18/disabling-mc40-home-button-with-a-custom-intent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/18/disabling-mc40-home-button-with-a-custom-intent/</guid>
      <description>Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve published another post that explain how to disable the Home Button on all the Zebra&amp;rsquo;s Android devices that are supported by Mx v4.3+.
Intro Zebra Technologies&amp;rsquo; devices are purpose built to be single use devices. Having an OS like Android nowadays provides a lot of flexibility&amp;hellip; sometimes a bit too much.
With this idea in mind, the Android version used on these devices sometimes provide some nice surprise, like an Intent to disable the omnipresent Android&amp;rsquo;s Home button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Zebra&#39;s EMDK project using SDK Platform 23</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2015/11/25/building-zebras-emdk-project-using-sdk-platform-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 09:54:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2015/11/25/building-zebras-emdk-project-using-sdk-platform-23/</guid>
      <description>Note: EMDK 4.0 is now documenting this method to add com.symbol.emdk.jar as a dependency There&amp;rsquo;s a recurring question coming to me and to Launchpad&amp;rsquo;s forums lately:
How can I compile my Android app, using Zebra&amp;rsquo;s EMDK, if I need the latest support library?
Some background With the Android tools moving super-fast (Android studio v1.0 launched at the beginning of 2015, the latest stable release is v1.4.1, we already have v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the SDCard Path on Android devices</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2014/10/19/finding-the-sdcard-path-on-android-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 20:55:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2014/10/19/finding-the-sdcard-path-on-android-devices/</guid>
      <description>With Motorola Solutions we&amp;rsquo;re busy finishing the first round of Android Developer&amp;rsquo;s Kitchens around Europe. Just in time to prepare for the Enterprise App Forum in Brussels!.
The nice things of these events is the interaction with our partners and theirs real live problem!
Last week I got an interesting question regarding our TC55:
How can I programmatically get the path for the SDCard on the TC55?
That&amp;rsquo;s a good question; usually you don&amp;rsquo;t want to insert in your code the dependency to an hard coded path!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting device info from MSI Android devices</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2014/09/02/getting-device-info-from-msi-android-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 11:56:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2014/09/02/getting-device-info-from-msi-android-devices/</guid>
      <description>The good old ways! On Symbol/MSI Windows Mobile devices, we where providing some APIs in the EMDK to get additional information. Looking into the Resource Coordinator is possible to find APIs like:
 RCM_GetESN() - retrieves the device electronic serial number RCM_GetUniqueUnitId() - retrieves the unique unit identification number RCM_GetVersion() - retrieves version information etc&amp;hellip;  &amp;hellip;and we don&amp;rsquo;t have anything like this in the Android EMDK. WHY?
Simply because the functionality is already included in the standard Android SDK.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>