<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rhomobile on Pietro F. Maggi</title>
    <link>http://pietromaggi.com/topics/rhomobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rhomobile on Pietro F. Maggi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2013-2018 Pietro F. Maggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 13:01:48 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://pietromaggi.com/topics/rhomobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhodes 5.0.2 and Visual Studio 2008 Localized edition</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/08/22/rhodes-5.0.2-and-visual-studio-2008-localized-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 13:01:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/08/22/rhodes-5.0.2-and-visual-studio-2008-localized-edition/</guid>
      <description>Oh the joy of a new RhoMobile version!
Creating new virtual machines and finally deciding that is time to leave the old trusty Windows XP and jump on the new Windows 7 with 63+1 bits. Oh man! what a pleasant use of time :-)
On top of this I wanted to spin the setup a bit and decided to use a localized version of Visual Studio 2008&amp;hellip; what can go wrong with it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring RhoMobile Suite v5.0 on a clean OS X Mavericks machine</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/08/11/configuring-rhomobile-suite-v5.0-on-a-clean-os-x-mavericks-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 09:57:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/08/11/configuring-rhomobile-suite-v5.0-on-a-clean-os-x-mavericks-machine/</guid>
      <description>RhoMobile Suite v5.0 The new main release of Rhodes, RhoElements and RhoConnect had just been released a couple of weeks ago during OSCON. It&amp;rsquo;s now time to install it and start building some mobile apps!
In this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to help you installing RMSv5.0 on a new OS X Mavericks machine and install everything that is needed to build iOS and Android applications, the only pre-requisite is to have a valid OS X Mavericks license installed on a Mac or inside a virtual machine&amp;hellip; on a Mac :-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhodes tips &amp; tricks</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/30/rhodes-tips--tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 13:56:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/30/rhodes-tips--tricks/</guid>
      <description>How to rebuild the rhodes gem git clone https://github.com/rhomobile/rhodes.git cd rhodes git checkout 3-5-stable  make and commit changes if needed, then:
rm -rf * git reset --hard git pull  Otherwise directly
rake gem  Copy files where you need it (on a different machine) gem install -l rhodes-3.5.1.13.2 (version given as an example)
Rhodes Database encryption Rhodes uses SQLite as database engine on all the supported platforms and, to provide encryption support we use different solutions depending by the target platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I like to talk about open source projects</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/28/why-i-like-to-talk-about-open-source-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 21:33:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/28/why-i-like-to-talk-about-open-source-projects/</guid>
      <description>Since I joined the RhoMobile group of Motorola Solutions as EIA pre-sale Technical Architect, I started to get disparate question regarding features of the Suite.
Something on the line:
 How is possible to launch an external application from a Rhodes one? I tried different APIs and nothing seems to work&amp;hellip; Looking on the support matrix of the APIs for different OSes, it seems that X is supported on platform Y but I&amp;rsquo;m not able to make it working&amp;hellip;  Usually I try to figure out the answer for these question by myself, it&amp;rsquo;s always useful getting a better understanding of the tool I usually talk about (and it&amp;rsquo;s probably the part of my job that I like the most: finding solutions to problems).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>