<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Pietro F. Maggi</title>
    <link>https://pietromaggi.com/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Pietro F. Maggi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2013-2018 Pietro F. Maggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 14:34:27 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pietromaggi.com/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving into Android source code</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/02/diving-into-android-source-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 14:34:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/02/diving-into-android-source-code/</guid>
      <description>Why dive into Android code? When you&amp;rsquo;ve to write applications for Android, you&amp;rsquo;re targeting a giant moving API surface, sometimes you can be surprised of some different behavior in different Android versions or with an API call that is not well documented, so having the option to delve into Android Source Code is a great opportunity.
A lot of things can be written on how to do this, there&amp;rsquo;s some documentation available on AOSP website, however I think that the best starting point is a video tutorial by NewCircle&amp;rsquo;s Instructor Dave Smith on this very topic:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I like to talk about open source projects</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/28/why-i-like-to-talk-about-open-source-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 21:33:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/28/why-i-like-to-talk-about-open-source-projects/</guid>
      <description>Since I joined the RhoMobile group of Motorola Solutions as EIA pre-sale Technical Architect, I started to get disparate question regarding features of the Suite.
Something on the line:
 How is possible to launch an external application from a Rhodes one? I tried different APIs and nothing seems to work&amp;hellip; Looking on the support matrix of the APIs for different OSes, it seems that X is supported on platform Y but I&amp;rsquo;m not able to make it working&amp;hellip;  Usually I try to figure out the answer for these question by myself, it&amp;rsquo;s always useful getting a better understanding of the tool I usually talk about (and it&amp;rsquo;s probably the part of my job that I like the most: finding solutions to problems).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>