<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Pietro F. Maggi</title>
    <link>http://pietromaggi.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Pietro F. Maggi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2013-2016 Pietro F. Maggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 20:50:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pietromaggi.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/09/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 20:50:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/09/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time for revamping a bit this blog.&lt;br /&gt;
From a technical point of view, I struggled with octopress v2.x to keep this blog aligned across the multiple machine I use in my work/life. Octopress v3 is supposed to solve most of the issue that plagued me over these years but, I wanted to test something a bit different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New year new static blog generator. Given that I want to spend some time evaluating &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; I decided to give &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend much time on the layout and the style of this site. My main concern is to be able to post content regularly, something that is not so easy, given the rate I had releasing new content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, back on track for 2016, I want to release new content on this site, and I hope that this new platform will support me well.
At this moment I&amp;rsquo;ve moved all the previous content, correcting few typos in the process, using one of the vanilla themes available.
I&amp;rsquo;ll will probably spend some time in the future to refine the layout, but this is more or less it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another change is the comment section, that will go life with one of the free discussion platform available, still have to decide which one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you enjoy the change and, more important, which topics you&amp;rsquo;ll like that I cover here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 New Year resolutions</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/01/2014-new-year-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 17:41:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/01/2014-new-year-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blog-a-bit-more:3ffa1135a53f35cda7dcf694bab43f34&#34;&gt;Blog a bit more&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s been one of my goal for a long time, and something that I always suggest to people to increase their &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codusoperandi.com/posts/increasing-your-luck-surface-area&#34;&gt;&amp;laquo;Luck Surface Area&amp;raquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case I can add an additional goal: keep track of what I do, tricks that I find and document procedure, fixes and workarounds.
That&amp;rsquo;s always a bit of a pain point for me: I manage to do something and then in six months (or six hours) I forgot how I&amp;rsquo;ve done it and I need to start from scratch&amp;hellip; &lt;strong&gt;Never More&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;content-in-markdown:3ffa1135a53f35cda7dcf694bab43f34&#34;&gt;Content in Markdown&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s one of the key technical decisions that I already have clear in mind, the content I&amp;rsquo;m going to produce will be in pure text, using &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; formatting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;choosing-a-blog-engine-and-an-hosting-platform:3ffa1135a53f35cda7dcf694bab43f34&#34;&gt;Choosing a blog engine and an hosting platform&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend a lot of time setting up a system at this moment, I prefer to use my time for other things!
GitHub offer a nice way to have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;git repository used as a blog source&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a no-brainer for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static site generators like &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekill&lt;/a&gt; are another &lt;em&gt;no brainer&lt;/em&gt;. In my case I prefer to have some helps so I&amp;rsquo;m going to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org/&#34;&gt;octopress&lt;/a&gt; starting with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheChymera/Koenigspress&#34;&gt;KoenigsPress&lt;/a&gt; theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hosting-solutions:3ffa1135a53f35cda7dcf694bab43f34&#34;&gt;Hosting solutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-my-custom-domain:3ffa1135a53f35cda7dcf694bab43f34&#34;&gt;Setting up my custom domain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end I used godaddy.com to buy the domain pietromaggi.com for the next 10 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to find a nice coupon and after few minutes I was able to have everything setup correctly.
Some additional information are available on stackoverflow and this &lt;a href=&#34;http://learnaholic.me/2012/10/10/deploying-octopress-to-github-pages-and-setting-custom-subdomain-cname/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;documenting-my-writing-process:3ffa1135a53f35cda7dcf694bab43f34&#34;&gt;Documenting my writing process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;rake new_post[&amp;quot;my new great post&amp;quot;]
rake preview
git status
git add .
git commit -m &amp;quot;Added new great post&amp;quot;
git push origin source
rake gen_deploy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll finally start to crank out some content!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 in numbers</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/31/2013-in-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 20:52:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/31/2013-in-numbers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-an-interesting-year:51abfbfcacde8f43d827325a2afc34bf&#34;&gt;What an interesting year!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first year that I joined a regional team and this involved a lot of travel (12900 flight hours) across all EMEA.
Has been a blast meeting a lot of end-users, partners and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started doing my &amp;laquo;RhoMobile Developer Roadshow&amp;raquo;, usually a one man show with up to three events a week for a total of 22 cities, from Lisbon to Dubai, and from Capetown to Helsinki.
Has been a blast, physically and emotionally! and I really enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So 2013 has been an year where I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that I like to travel, especially to meet people and chat with them about technology. I like to train/coach people, I now have few end-users/partners direct relations as the go-to guy for RhoMobile projects and I like to speak in public, both at our small events and at big technology conferences.  I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered this last point presenting at a couple of DroidCon events later in 2013 (London and Amsterdam).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013 included a new manager (Hi James, thanks for all the support) and a new team: the dynamic duo with Paul&amp;amp;Pietro. By the end of 2013 Paul decided to follow a different professional path so, all the best to him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I&amp;rsquo;m ready for 2014!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>