<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Pietro F. Maggi</title>
    <link>http://pietromaggi.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Pietro F. Maggi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2013-2016 Pietro F. Maggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 20:50:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://pietromaggi.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/09/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 20:50:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/09/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Time for revamping a bit this blog.
From a technical point of view, I struggled with octopress v2.x to keep this blog aligned across the multiple machine I use in my work/life. Octopress v3 is supposed to solve most of the issue that plagued me over these years but, I wanted to test something a bit different.
New year new static blog generator. Given that I want to spend some time evaluating Go I decided to give Hugo a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 New Year resolutions</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/01/2014-new-year-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 17:41:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/01/2014-new-year-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>Blog a bit more That&amp;rsquo;s been one of my goal for a long time, and something that I always suggest to people to increase their &amp;laquo;Luck Surface Area&amp;raquo;.
In my case I can add an additional goal: keep track of what I do, tricks that I find and document procedure, fixes and workarounds. That&amp;rsquo;s always a bit of a pain point for me: I manage to do something and then in six months (or six hours) I forgot how I&amp;rsquo;ve done it and I need to start from scratch&amp;hellip; Never More</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 in numbers</title>
      <link>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/31/2013-in-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 20:52:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>http://pietromaggi.com/2013/12/31/2013-in-numbers/</guid>
      <description>What an interesting year! This is the first year that I joined a regional team and this involved a lot of travel (12900 flight hours) across all EMEA. Has been a blast meeting a lot of end-users, partners and colleagues.
I&amp;rsquo;ve started doing my &amp;laquo;RhoMobile Developer Roadshow&amp;raquo;, usually a one man show with up to three events a week for a total of 22 cities, from Lisbon to Dubai, and from Capetown to Helsinki.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>