<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tricks on Pietro F. Maggi</title>
    <link>https://pietromaggi.com/tags/tricks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tricks on Pietro F. Maggi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2013-2019 Pietro F. Maggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 17:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pietromaggi.com/tags/tricks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling Home Button on Zebra Android devices</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2016/08/01/disabling-home-button-on-zebra-android-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2016/08/01/disabling-home-button-on-zebra-android-devices/</guid>
      <description>Intro I presented in the past a method to disable the Home Button on Zebra&amp;rsquo;s MC40 Android device, using a custom intent1. After having published it, I got some enquiries, about having the same behaviour on other Zebra&amp;rsquo;s devices. Well, it turns out that there&amp;rsquo;s now a &amp;laquo;standard&amp;raquo; way to do this in Zebra&amp;rsquo;s Mx extension using the UI Manager profile. This post is going to show how to implement a simple application that can disable the Home Button on all Zebra&amp;rsquo;s devices that have Mx v4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling MC40 Home Button with a custom intent</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/18/disabling-mc40-home-button-with-a-custom-intent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2016/01/18/disabling-mc40-home-button-with-a-custom-intent/</guid>
      <description>Note: _I&amp;rsquo;ve published another post that explain how to disable the Home Button on all the Zebra&amp;rsquo;s Android devices that are supported by Mx v4.3+._
Intro Zebra Technologies&amp;rsquo; devices are purpose built to be single use devices. Having an OS like Android nowadays provides a lot of flexibility&amp;hellip; sometimes a bit too much.
With this idea in mind, the Android version used on these devices sometimes provide some nice surprise, like an Intent to disable the omnipresent Android&amp;rsquo;s Home button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Back Button and Enterprise Browser</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2015/09/25/android-back-button-and-enterprise-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 11:33:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2015/09/25/android-back-button-and-enterprise-browser/</guid>
      <description>Edit Enteprise Browser v1.3 introduced a change that requires to enable FunctionKeysCapturable to be able to use the KeyCapture API.
To do this you need to update your Config.xml with:
&amp;lt;FunctionKeysCapturable value=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;  Enterprise Browser Enterprise Browser is Zebra Technologies&amp;rsquo; Industrial Browser built for our Rugged Devices, we support most of our Windows Mobile/Windows CE devices and Android devices.
This product is usually used with existing web application that cannot be updated/modified moving from one device to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little command line tricks</title>
      <link>https://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/10/little-command-line-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 19:37:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>pfm@pietromaggi.com (Pietro F. Maggi)</author>
      <guid>https://pietromaggi.com/2014/01/10/little-command-line-tricks/</guid>
      <description>This is a different blog, more a remainder for me than anything else. Hope that someone else can find these useful&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;re for me!
Recover a failed download with curl: curl -C - -o partially_downloaded_file &#39;www.example.com/path/to/the/file&#39;  Burn a playable DVD from a VIDEO_TS folder After searching the forums and trying various things, I still couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a quick, reliable, free method of burning a VIDEO_TS folder to a pure UDF DVD, so that it would play in regular DVD players, as well trigger DVD Player to start up automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>